const W00quiz = [
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q1",
        question: " The frequency range of the UK 10m amateur band is:",
        options: [
            "3.500-3.800 MHz",
            "10.100-10.150 MHz",
            "28.000-29.700MHz",
            "10000-10125MHz"
        ],
        correct: 2,
        explanation: "First thing to do is to convert 10m to a frequency in MHz. You previously did that with a conversion chart, you will now need to calculate it.The easy version is 300 ÷ metres = MHz, so 300/10 = 30 MHz; you may have learned that in your Foundation training. The nearest to that is 28.000-29.700 MHz, making ‘c’ the correct answer.",
        lookup: "See the Intermediate Licence Parameters chart in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q2",
        question: "As an Intermediate Licence Holder operating on 1.900 MHz, what is the maximum power you can apply to your antenna feedpoint?",
        options: [
            "100W",
            "40W",
            "32W",
            "1W"
        ],
        correct: 2,
        explanation: "It is important to note that whilst 100W is seen as the maximum power for an Intermediate Licence holder, this does not apply to all bands and all four answers feature in the Licence Schedule (Intermediate Licence Parameters). 1.900 MHz sits in the band 1.850-2.000 MHz and the maximum power for that band is 32 W.",
        lookup: "See the Intermediate Licence Parameters chart in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q3",
        question: "Which of the following UK amateur bands is available to the Intermediate Licenceholder as a Primary allocation, with no specific caveats and a maximum power of 100 W ?",
        options: [
            "1.810-1.830 MHz",
            "18.068-18.168 MHz",
            "431.0-432.0 MHz",
            "432.0-435.0 MHz"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        explanation: "‘a’ is not the one because it has a caveat relating to non￾interference. ‘b’ has Primary status, no caveats and a 100 W limit, so looks good, but let’s look at the others. ‘c’ has Secondary status, has caveats relating to proximity to Charing Cross, London, and a 40 W limit, so wrong on every count! ‘d’ is 100 W, has no caveats but is also a Secondary allocation, so not the one to go for.",
        lookup: "See the Intermediate Licence Parameters chart in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q4",
        question: " Which of the following best describes the unit of measurement for maximum power for your transmissions?",
        options: [
            "Peak Envelope Power in Watts on all bands",
            "Effective Radiated Power in Watts on all bands",
            "Effective Radiated Power in Watts on some bands with Input Power in Watts on other bands",
            "Peak Envelope Power in Watts on all bands with an Effective Radiated Power limit on some bands"
        ],
        correct: 3,
        explanation: "The top box of the fourth column in the Licence Parameters sets the limit as the ‘Maximum Peak Envelope Power level in Watts…’ so Peak Envelope Power must feature in the correct answer, and that rules out ‘b’ and ‘c’.So is it ‘a’ or ‘d’? ‘a’ is true but, you should also note that some bands add ‘ERP’, or Effective Radiated Power, making‘d’ the most complete, or ‘best’, answer.",
        lookup: " Intermediate Licence Parameters chart in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q5",
        question: " On which frequencies in the 20m band would you find the International Beacon Project transmissions?",
        options: [
            "14,000-14,060 kHz",
            "14,070-14,089 kHz",
            "14,089-14,099 kHz",
            "14,099-14,101 kHz"
        ],
        correct: 3,
        explanation: "The International Beacon Project (IBP) has allocations on most Band Plans. On the 14 MHz(20m) Band Plan, the allocation is 14.099 to 14.101 MHz, or 14,099 to 14,101 kHz.",
        lookup: "See the Intermediate Licence Amateur Radio Band Plans page in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q6",
        question: "Which frequency in the 2m band is used for the weekly RSGB News Broadcast using the callsign GB2RS?",
        options: [
            "144.8250 MHz",
            "145.5250 MHz",
            "145.5500 MHz",
            "145.8000 MHz"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        explanation: "Simple look up question, ‘a’ is for DV Internet Gateways, ‘b’ is for GB2RS News Broadcasts, ‘c’ is for Rally / Exhibition Talk-in stations and ‘d’ is for Space Communications, for example with the International Space Station.",
        lookup: "See the Intermediate Licence Amateur Radio Band Plans page in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q7",
        question: " On which frequencies in the 2m band would you find Propagation Beacons?",
        options: [
            "144.150-144.400 MHz",
            "144.400-144.490 MHz",
            "144.500-144.794 MHz",
            "144.990-145.1935 MHz"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        explanation: "Simple look up question, ‘a’ is for Telegraphy, MGM and SSB, ‘b’ is for Propagation Beacons only, ‘c’ is for All Modes and ‘d’ is for Repeater Inputs.",
        lookup: "See the Intermediate Licence Amateur Radio Band Plans page in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q8",
        question: " Intermediate Licence holders must note that ‘specific conditions’ apply on the 2m band within 50 km of:",
        options: [
            "Belfast",
            "Glasgow",
            "Cambridge",
            "Scarborough"
        ],
        correct: 3,
        explanation: "Not so simple to look up, but it is included in the last 144MHz (2m) Licence Note(not numbered). The specific conditions referred to can be found in an Ofcom document called the Notice of Coordination, which does not feature in the Intermediate syllabus, but is part of the Licence Terms & Conditions you must comply with.",
        lookup: "See the Intermediate Licence Amateur Radio Band Plans page in EX308",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q9",
        question: "What kind of access is recommended for FM Repeaters and Gateways?",
        options: [
            "CTCSS",
            "Tone Burst",
            "Tone Based PIN",
            "Digital Thumbprint"
        ],
        correct: 0,
        explanation: "Not so simple to look up, but it is included in the ‘Notes to the bandplans’ under FM Repeater & Gateway Access.",
        lookup: "See the Intermediate Licence Amateur Radio Band Plans page in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q10",
        question: "If the symbol for reactance is 'X', and the symbol for inductance is 'L', which of the following could you use to work out the reactance of an inductor(XL)?",
        options: [
            "1 ÷ 2πfC",
            "R1+R2+R3",
            "2πfL",
            "fλ"
        ],
        correct: 2,
        explanation: "This may feel totally alien because it uses terms you have not yet studied, but you are provided with a Formula Sheet in EX308 to look up the formula. You should be able to find a formula for X relating to an inductor(XL) in the first column, about half-way down.You should also be able to spot that ‘c’ is in that formula.",
        lookup: "See the Formula Sheet page in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q11",
        question: " If you were given the frequency of an amateur signal, and its wavelength, which of the following could you use to work out its velocity?",
        options: [
            "1 ÷ 2πfC",
            "R1+R2+R3",
            "2πfL",
            "fλ"
        ],
        correct: 3,
        explanation: "This may feel totally alien because it uses terms you have not yet studied, but you are provided with a Formula Sheet in EX308 to look up the formula.You should be able to find a formula using f, for frequency, and wavelength (the symbol Lambda λ) in the second column, near the bottom.You should also be able to spot that ‘d’ is that formula.",
        lookup: " See the Intermediate Licence Formula Sheet page in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q12",
        question: "Some resistors are marked with a colour code to show their value. Which number is represented by blue?",
        options: [
            "2",
            "4",
            "6",
            "8"
        ],
        correct: 2,
        explanation: "Simple look up question; ‘2’ is represented by the colour ‘Red’, 4 by ‘Yellow’, ‘6’ by ‘Blue’ and ‘8’ by ‘Grey’.",
        lookup: "See the Resistor Colour Code chart at the bottom of the Formula Sheet page in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q13",
        question: " Some resistors have a gold coloured band on them. That band can mean:",
        options: [
            "Divide the two previous bands by 5, or the tolerance is 1%",
            "Divide the two previous bands by 10, or the tolerance is 5%",
            "Divide the two previous bands by 5, or the tolerance is 10%",
            "Divide the two previous bands by 10, or the tolerance is 20%"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        explanation: "Simple look up question; ‘gold’ can either mean that the marked value of the resistor has to be divided by 10, or that the whole value is +/-5% its marked value.",
        lookup: "See the Resistor Colour Code chart at the bottom of the Formula Sheet page in EX308.",
        syllabus: "0"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q14",
        question: "What is the purpose of the Licence Terms & Conditions relating to EMF assessments?",
        options: [
            "To limit the distance that each Licence level can achieve",
            "To prevent Licence Holders exceeding their maximum permitted RF output powers",
            "To ensure that all electronic equipment is able to operate without causing interference to other electronic equipment",
            "To ensure that members of the public are not exposed to non-ionising electro-magnetic radiation above the recommended levels."
        ],
        correct: 3,
        explanation: "Foundation revision; the UK Licence prohibits operation of any transmitter unless the Licence Holder can ensure that the general public are not exposed to levels of non-ionising electro-magnetic radiation above the recommended levels. ‘a’ and ‘b’ are both wrong because the same restrictions apply to all Licence levels. ‘c’ is wrong because that relates to EMC, not EMF",
        lookup: "See page 23 of the Intermediate Licence textbook or BBDL EMF Catch-Up paper.",
        syllabus: "1g.1"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 Q15",
        question: "Which of the following transmit powers would NOT require a detailed EMF assessment?",
        options: [
            "5W ERP",
            "12W EIRP",
            "50W ERP",
            "50W EIRP"
        ],
        correct: 0,
        explanation: "Foundation revision; if your initial assessment shows that you are never going to transmit more than 10W EIRP you do not need to do a detailed assessment. That equates to about 6.1W ERP. Only answer ‘a’ is below that threshold.",
        lookup: "See page 23 of the Intermediate Licence textbookk, or BBDL EMF Catch-Up paper",
        syllabus: "1g.1"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 extra q1",
        question: "Battery Internal Resistance: A battery has an electromotive force (EMF) of 12 V. When a current of 2 A is drawn from the battery, the terminal voltage is measured to be 10 V. What is the internal resistance of the battery?",
        options: [
            "1Ω",
            "2Ω",
            "5Ω",
            "6Ω"
        ],
        correct: 0,
        explanation: "The fundamental relationship we'll use is the terminal voltage (Vt​) of a battery, which is its electromotive force (E) minus the voltage drop across its internal resistance (r) when a current (I) is flowing:<br>Vt ​= E − I × r <br>We also know that the terminal voltage is the voltage across the external load(Rext), so <br>Vt ​= I × Rext​.<br><br>Combining these, we get <br>E =I × (Rext + r). <br><br> Given: E=12 V, I=2 A, Vt​=10 V. <br><br>Using Vt ​= E − I × r<br>10V = 12V − (2A ×r)<br>2A × r=12V − 10V<br>2r = 2Ω<br>r=2/2 = 1Ω <br>Correct Answer: A) 1Ω.",
        lookup: "",
        syllabus: "2c.2"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 extra q2",
        question: "Battery Internal Resistance: A battery with an EMF of 9 V and an internal resistance of 0.5Ω is connected to an external resistor of 4Ω. What is the terminal voltage of the battery?",
        options: [
            "1 V",
            "2 V",
            "8 V",
            "9 V"
        ],
        correct: 2,
        explanation: "see extra Q1 for the approach",
        lookup: "",
        syllabus: "2c.2"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 extra q3",
        question: "Battery Internal Resistance: A power source has an EMF of 6 V and an internal resistance of 1.2Ω. If it is connected to a load resistor of 4.8Ω, what is the current flowing through the circuit?",
        options: [
            "0.5 A",
            "1.0 A",
            "1.2 A",
            "5.0 A"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        explanation: "see extra Q1 for the approach",
        lookup: "",
        syllabus: "2c.2"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 extra q4",
        question: "Battery Internal Resistance: A battery is supplying a current of 3 A to a circuit. The terminal voltage of the battery is 4.5 V, and its internal resistance is 0.2Ω. What is the EMF of the battery?",
        options: [
            "3.9 V",
            "4.3 V",
            "4.7 V",
            "5.1 V"
        ],
        correct: 3,
        explanation: "see extra Q1 for the approach",
        lookup: "",
        syllabus: "2c.2"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 extra q5",
        question: "Battery Internal Resistance: A battery has an EMF of 15 V and an internal resistance of 0.8Ω. When connected to an external circuit, a current of 5 A flows. What is the voltage dropped across the internal resistance of the battery?",
        options: [
            "0.8 V",
            "4.0 V",
            "11.0 V",
            "15.0 V"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        explanation: "see extra Q1 for the approach",
        lookup: "",
        syllabus: "2c.2"
    },
    {
        source: "BBDL Intermediate Quiz W00 extra q6",
        question: "Battery Internal Resistance: A battery with an EMF of 7.5 V and an internal resistance of 0.3Ω is connected to an external resistor. If the terminal voltage is 6 V, what is the value of the external resistor?",
        options: [
            "0.3Ω",
            "1.2Ω",
            "2.0Ω",
            "2.4Ω"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        explanation: "see extra Q1 for the approach",
        lookup: "",
        syllabus: "2c.2"
    },
]

export default W00quiz